这里太冷了
我周末要乘游艇去圣普里斯卡
什么情况
只是有点气流
航空管制那里报道
Air traffic control's reporting
有一架直升机出现事故
a helicopter in distress.
为什么每次我来
Why is it every time I come to visit,
就出各种事故
all hell is breaking loose?
糟了  要撞上新西弗大楼了
Oh no, it's gonna hit the new Seaver Building.
没事了  巴里去帮他们了
It's okay. Barry's on it.
我去帮谁了
What am I on?
总是喜欢闪亮登场
Always have to make an entrance,
是不是  闪电小子
don't you, Kid Flash?
这还用说
What can I say?
回来感觉真不错
It's great to be back.
闪 电 侠
第六季
第十四集
一朵莲花
A lotus flower.
这真是太美了
Okay, that is seriously beautiful.
你绝对得教教我
Yeah, I'm definitely gonna need you
怎么做到这个
to teach me how to do that.
莲花是八个祥瑞符号之一
The lotus is one of the eight auspicious symbols
代表这纯净和放下执念
meaning purity and renunciation,
我现在正在佛教尼姑无垢的指导下
practice which I'm currently being guided through
修炼这种心境
by Bhikkhuni Amala, the Buddhist nun
她是我所在的维和部队指派的佛教尼姑
assigned to my Peace Corps camp.
真棒  纯净以及放下执念
Wow, purity and renunciation.
对我来说那就是再多喝点葡萄酒
Guess that means more wine for me.
身处此处  和家人团聚  结识新朋友
Just being here celebrating with family, new friends
就是我所追求的快乐了
is all the joy I need.
瞧瞧你  这么努力地禅修
Look at you getting your Zen on.
能看见他们了
It's working.
那是谁
Who is that?
那是我弟弟  沃利
That's my brother, Wally.
他看上去好开心
He looks so happy.
要是我在场就好了
I wish I was there.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我没法维持这个窗口更久
I couldn't hold the window any longer.
没关系
It's okay.
即便只有一秒
It was so good to see them,
能再见到他们也很开心的
even if it was just for a second.
你想念你的家人了
You miss your family.
是的  我已经被困在这里几周了
Yeah, well, I've been trapped in here for weeks and...
失去了时间意识  就好像在梦境里
Losing my sense of time like I'm in some sort of dream.
与此同时  我的家人就在那里
All the while, my family is out there
和那个  那个东西
with that--that thing
不是我的东西
that isn't me.
希望他们不会像约瑟夫忘掉我一样
I hope they don't forget about you
那么快就忘掉你
as quickly as my Joseph forgot about me.
他曾经每天都来到镜子前
He used to come to my mirror every day and try
想方设法把我弄出去
to figure out a way to get me out.
他知道你还在这里吗
Does he know that you're still in here?
我不确定
I don't know.
巴里称我为他的避雷针
Barry calls me his lightning rod.
他曾经说无论我在宇宙任何地方
He used to say that he could find me
他都会找到我
anywhere in the universe.
似乎他会为你做任何事情
Seems like there's nothing he wouldn't do for you.
我已经多年没有见过我的丈夫了
I haven't seen my husband in years.
我已经72个月没有碰过他
I haven't touched him in 72 months...
那是312个星期
312 weeks...
2190天
2,190 days.
2190  2190
2,190. 2,190.
2,190.
2190  2190
2,190. 2,190.
伊娃  听我说  深呼吸
Eva, listen to me. Breathe.
2,190.
2190  2190
2,190. 2,190.
爱瑞丝  你还好吗
Hey, Iris, everything okay?
我没事
Um, yeah.
大家好  地球上的人类
Greetings, Earth Prime-lings!
宝贝  你提前回来了
Babe, you're home early!
-你看起来...  -不错吧
- Wow, you look-- - I know, right?
-兄弟你好  -你好
- Wow, hey, bud. - Hey.
-你终于回来了  -是的
- You're finally back. - I am.
经过了一段时间
Well, after a while,
所有危机后的异常搜寻
all the post-Crisis anomaly hunting
已经开始影响你们了
starts to catch up with you--
此外  我要把这些衣服上的
that, and I wanted to wash all the Atlantean fish smell
亚特兰大鱼味全都洗掉
off of these clothes.
隔空拥抱你
Hugs from here.
欢迎回家  你们用不着这么隆重
"Welcome home"? You guys shouldn't have.
欢迎回家
可惜
Shame.
很高兴见到你  朋友
Well, it's good to see you, friend.
沃利·韦斯特
Wally West?
什么  你都去哪里了
What? Where have you been?
欢迎回家
Welcome home--
欢迎回家  我懂了
"Welcome home"-- I see.
这是欢迎你的派对  不是我的
I am crashing your party.
你知道你回来我们总是很高兴   鳄鱼邓迪
You know we're always happy to have you back, crocodile Dundee.
澳大利亚冒险喜剧电影
来  我给你倒杯酒喝
Come on, let me make you a drink.
你太懂我了
You know me too well.
宝贝  我想我们也许该回家了
Okay, babe, I think we should probably get you home.
嗯  你说得对
Yeah. Yeah, you're right.
亚特兰蒂斯现在是早上四点
It's, like, 4:00 in the morning in Atlantis,
也许该去睡了
so, yeah, should probably go to bed.
我们应该回家  让保姆休息
Yeah, we should get home and relieve the babysitter.
亲爱的  我要回办公室一趟
Hon, I gotta go back to the office.
什么
What?
自从纳什搬到对面  我的工作都没法完成
I can't get any work done since Nash moved in across the hall.
我可以送你
I can give you a ride.
我要去《公民报》上晚班
I'm working a late shift at the "Citizen."
好极了
Perfect.
-晚安  各位  -晚安
- Good night, guys. - Good night.
拜拜
Bye-bye.
我们来收拾
We got this.
不和你们抢
Okay, won't argue with that.
天呐  他们...  准备好了吗  开始
Boy, they-- you ready? Let's do it.
你怎么了
Whoa, what was that?
没事
Nothing.
只是
It was,
出了点小问题
just a hiccup.
只是出了点小问题
Just a little hiccup.
小问题  那是第一次吗
A hiccup? Is that the first one?
巴里
Hey, Barry.
你还好吧
Are you all right, man?
不  我的确出现了几个小状况
No, I mean, I've had a few little things.
身上还是酸痛
It's still sore.
我的极速治愈有点奇怪
My speed healing was weird for a little bit,
但是现在好了
but, I mean, it's fine now.
只是我的身体还没从危机中完全复原
It was just my body still recovering from Crisis.
巴里
Barry.
我回来不只是为了看望家人
I didn't just come back to see family.
最近  我发现神速力
Lately, I've been sensing that there's something wrong
有点不对劲
with the Speed Force.
你感觉到神速力受到了干扰
A disturbance in the Speed Force, you feel.
尤达学得太烂了
That's terrible Yoda.
佛教尼姑无垢帮我找到了
Bhikkhuni Amala helped me discover a way
与神速力沟通的方式
to communicate with the Speed Force--
通过投射我的意识来寻求指引
to seek guidance by projecting my consciousness into it
同时能离开我的身体
while leaving my body behind.
厉害  我一直都做不到
Damn, I've never been able to do that.
一般情况下都是顺其而来
It just usually comes to me.
以你母亲的样子出现对吧
As your mother, right?
我记得在闪电风暴里见过
Yeah, I remember from the lightning storm.
但是我的不一样
For me, it's different.
更像是脑海里有个声音在指引着我
It's more of a voice inside my head guiding me,
但是几个月前  那个声音消失了
but a few months ago, that voice just went quiet.
每当我想试着接触  都是一片寂静
Now every time I try to reach out-- silence.
你上一次和神速力接触是什么时候的事
When was the last time the Speed Force came to you?
有一段时间了
I mean, it's been a while,
但是我觉得
but, listen, I-I-I-I-I don't think
神速力没有问题
there's anything wrong with the Speed Force.
我是说  如果有问题它会让我知道的
You know, I mean, if there was, it would let me know, you know?
不然我  再说了
Or I don't--besides,
我肯定这事有更简单的解释
I'm sure there's a simple explanation for all this.
相信我
Trust me.
一杯燕麦奶震波奇诺  特热加两糖
One oat milk vibe-accino, extra hot with two sugars
还有三薄层肉桂带走
and three short sprinkles of cinnamon to go.
我说的是三糖和两薄层肉桂
I said three sugars and two sprinkles of cinnamon.
美国蠢货
怎么回事
亚历克西
Alexi?
我还以为你会简单的
I thought you'd go down easy
死在你那直升机中
in that fancy helicopter of yours.
我猜现在
I guess now...
要来硬的了
弗里达
Frida.
你好  玛丽亚
Hello, Maria.
再见了
玛丽亚
Maria!
玛丽亚·沃尔科娃  俄国名流
Maria Volkova, Russian socialite.
一分钟前  她还在这嘬咖啡
One minute, she's here sipping java,
下一分钟就变成了木乃伊吗
and the next minute, she's a mummy?
这就是我从直升机上救下的女人
This is the same woman I saved from the helicopter,
但是她很年轻  充满活力
but she was young. She was full of life.
基于她的单倍体T细胞受体来看
Well, based on her signal joint T-cell receptors,
她死时体征是110岁
she was 110 years old when she died.
我去
Damn.
所以那个直升机意外  不是随机的
So the helicopter accident-that wasn't random.
有人在针对她
Someone targeted her.
不只是随便的某人
Not just any someone.
你看到身体的动能能量了吗
You see the kinetic energy levels on the body?
几乎接近于零
Yeah, they're almost zero,
就像是某人移除了他们一样
like someone removed it all.
因此减慢了受害者
Therefore slowing down the victim,
所以玛丽亚才老了这么多
which is how Maria was aged so many years.
我是说  现实时间可能才过去一秒
I mean, real time, it would have been like a second passed,
但是对于她来说几乎是一个世纪
but, for her, it was almost a century.
为什么这个感觉如此熟悉
Why does this feel so familiar?
之前不是有个人  可以减慢...
Wasn't there someone who could, like, slow--
如果你想的是乌龟人...
If you're thinking it's Turtle...
-对  -错了
- Yeah. - It's not.
这个超能力者不仅能减慢时间
This meta doesn't just slow down time.
她可以创造势能能量护盾
She can create potential energy force fields
保卫受害人个体
around individual victims,
在一眨眼之间让他们老去一个世纪
aging them centuries in the blink of an eye.
这不是乌龟人  是乌龟人二代
This wasn't Turtle. This was Turtle 2.
抱歉  我只是在等着你
Sorry, I was just waiting
想出个更好的名字
for you to come up with a better name.
不  乌龟人二代  小而美
No, it's Turtle 2. Less is more.
重要的是她的真名
Well, what matters is her real name,
弗里达·诺维科夫女士
Mrs. Frida Novikov.
我们因为她在公寓里进行跨国贩毒
We busted her for running an international drug ring
抓过她  我们遣送她回了俄罗斯
out of her apartment. We deported her back to Russia.
显然  她没有待久
Well, apparently, she didn't stay put.
我旅行每到一处  都能听到诺维科夫的故事
Everywhere I went on my trip, I heard stories about Novikov.
我提早回家来检查她的老地盘
I came home early to check out her old haunts,
并且或许能找出她的真正目的
and maybe find a clue about what she's up to.
我只是没想到她也会回家
I just didn't expect she'd come back home too.
我们最好搞清楚她为什么回来
Well, we better figure out why she's back
趁她变老其他人之前
before she ages anybody else.
我去调出她的档案
Yeah, I'm gonna go pull her file.
好的  谢了
Okay. Thanks.
我去看看能不能找到方法
I'll see if I can work up a way to take
一劳永逸的解决她的能力
the wind out of her sails for good.
黑客神童回归了
The prodigal hacker returns.
来给我讲讲那伟大的
Regale me with the adventures
环球旅行家西斯科曼达洛人的冒险故事吧
of the great, globe-trotting Cisco-lorian.
我等下再详细告诉你
I'll tell you all about it later.
现在  我正试图解决能减慢时间的超能力者
Right now, I'm trying to stop a meta who can slow down time
重新设计终极速度-X的配方
by reworking the Velocity-X formula
来使她加速达到中和
to speed her up and neutralize
她的势能能量超能力  我要集中注意力
her kinetic energy meta-powers, so I'm gonna focus on that.
敲敲  博士  我只是需要你...
Knock-knock, Doc, I just need your--
我需要知道
I need to know if,
在你旅行中...
on your trip...
你有没有看到从别的地球来的人
you saw anyone else from any other Earths.
-其他人  -对的
- Other people? - That's right.
-从别的地球  -没错
- From other Earths? - That's right.
没有啊  因为任何
Uh, okay, not really, because any doppelgangers
设法来到这里的二重身
who managed to make it here--
现在都应该死掉了
they would all be dead by now
因为神经退化
due to neurological degeneration.
万一他们已经死了呢
What if they were already dead?
你是在逗我吧
You gotta be kidding me.
怎么了
What?
伟大的流言终结者竟然突然相信鬼了
The great myth buster suddenly believes in ghosts.
不是
No.
我指的不是鬼  我说的是幸存者
No, I'm not talking ghosts. I'm talking survivors.
原来是幸存者啊
Oh, survivors.
-是的  -当然了  好吓人啊
- Yeah. - Sure--spooky.
听着  幸存者  鬼  不管你怎么叫他们
Look, survivors, ghosts, whatever you wanna call them,
都是不可能的  危机确保了这一点
it's not possible. Crisis made sure of that.
-你还记得吗  -我
- Remember? - I--
你根本看不到任何像这样的事
You wouldn't have been able to see anything like that.
好吧
All right, fine,
那你在外面的时候肯定是错过了什么
well, then you missed something out there.
我错过了什么
I missed something?
你错过了是因为...
You missed something because--
你知不知道我花了
Do you know how many hours--
多少时间和精力
how much time and energy
记录我在那边看到的所有东西
I spent cataloguing everything I saw out there?
我需要你帮忙找到一个说得通的答案
I need your help finding an answer that makes sense! Ok?
-放下你的那个宝贝终极速度-F吧  -是X
- So drop your little Velocity-F. - X!
X  然后来帮我来找真正要紧的东西吧
X--and help me track something that really matters.
我在试图找到那个追踪了好几周的罪犯
I'm trying to find a criminal I've been after for weeks.
-那很重要  -只对于你来说
- That matters! - To you.
看来你经历这些旅行后
Well, I guess on all your travels
终于学会把注意力移到除你以外的人身上了
you finally learned to focus on someone else besides yourself--
才怪
not.
纳什  需要什么吗
Nash, need something?
不需要
Nope.
巴里还装作无事发生
Barry's acting like nothing is wrong.
我不应该为此沮丧
I shouldn't get frustrated.
无垢曾说过  自负乃平静之敌
Amala says, "Pride is the enemy of peace."
我觉得
You know, I don't think
巴里与神速力之间的联系
Barry will ever have the same relationship
不可能像你一样
with the Speed Force that you do.
至少在那件事之后
Not after what happened.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
其实  我不知道整个来龙去脉
Well, I don't know the full story,
但是上个秋天  巴里与神速力
but last fall, Barry and the Speed Force
发生了点事故
had an incident.
他没跟我讲过
He did not tell me that.
可能他还在鼓起勇气
Maybe he's trying to work up the nerve?
可能吧  但是如果你感觉到的干扰
Maybe, but if that disturbance you're sensing
是真的话  你还能在这浪费时间吗
is real, do you really have time to waste here?
说真的  你们两个真的是
Okay, you two are seriously
这个世界上最好看的一对姐弟了
the best looking siblings in the world.
无比法曾教过我们避免自我痴迷
The Abhidhamma teaches us to avoid self-infatuation,
但是我需要你拷贝一份发给我
but I may need you to forward me a copy of that one.
等会见
See you later.
相机是不是挺帅
Pretty cool camera, right?
我拜托西斯科从德国昆比实验室搞了一个给我
I asked Cisco to pick it up from Quimby Labs in Germany,
但是他绝对做改造了
but he definitely made some modifications.
你需要马上把那张照片删掉
You need to delete that photo right now.
为什么
Why?
我们不应该给《公民报》的员工拍照
We shouldn't be taking photos of "Citizen" Employees.
万一传到了网上
I mean, if that got online,
再来一个像霍西一样来自黑洞的刺客
another of Black Hole's assassins like Hoshi
-就能找到我们的行踪了  -对  抱歉
- could track our moves. - Right, sorry.
你去找乔谈了吗
Hey, did you talk to Joe?
他要调诺维科夫的档案
He was gonna pull Novikov's file.
你和神速力之间发生了什么  巴里
What happened between you and the Speed Force, Barry?
沃利  我正在处理案子
Wally, I'm working a case, all right?
如果有坏事发生  那可能就是
If something bad happened, That might be
导致我们超能力出问题的原因
what's causing all these problems with our powers.
你听着  你不知道你在说什么
You--listen, you don't know what you're talking about.
我相信你可以解决  巴里
I believe that you can solve this, Barry,
如果你面对神速力的话
if you face the Speed Force.
-我不能  -为什么
- I can't. - Why not?
-它不想和我对话  -你怎么知道
- It doesn't wanna talk to me. - How do you know that?
因为敌人用噩梦和幻觉
Because an enemy infected my mind
感染了我的大脑
with nightmares and visions.
当它想要帮助我的时候  我攻击了它
When it tried to help me, I attacked it,
如果你觉得神速力想听从我声音的话
so if you think the Speed Force wants to hear from me...
巴里
Barry.
那你就不明白
Then you--you don't understand
神速力想要什么
what the Speed Force wants.
巴里  我们已经在这了
Barry, we're already here.
我们在神速力中
We're in the Speed Force.
你把我带进来的吗
You took me in here?
不太对劲
Something is wrong.
我们得找到她
We need to find her.
那到底是什么
What the hell is that?
沃利
Wally.
这是我之前的房间
This is my old room.
什么
What?
怎么了
What's--what's going on?
神速力怎么了
What's happening to the Speed Force?
我们快死了  巴里·艾伦
We are dying, Barry Allen.
不会的
That's not...
怎么可能
How is that possible?
因为你的所作所为
Because of what you did.
不不  沃利  我们得回去
No, no, no, Wally, we have to go back.
我得和她说话  我得和她说话
I have to talk to her. I have to talk to her!
巴里  你做了什么
Barry, what did you do?
神速力  它快死了
The Speed Force--it's dying.
这是我们超能力出问题的原因
This is why our powers are broken.
这是我们这么久来一直感觉到的
This is what we have been sensing this whole time.
不  这不可能  好吧
Look, it's not-- it's not possible, all right?
神速力是能量的无穷来源
I mean, the Speed Force is an infinite source of energy.
就像重力或者光  不会随便就死的
It's like gravity or light. It doesn't just die.
不  不是随便死的  巴里
No, it didn't just die, Barry.
她说它快死了是因为你的所作所为
She said it's dying because of what you did.
巴里  是你的错
Barry, this is your fault!
拉姆齐感染了我  我别无选择
Ramsey was infecting me. I mean, I didn't have a choice.
我没说你对她做的
I'm not even talking about what you did to her.
我说的是你之后做的
I'm talking about what you did after.
几个月前你背叛了神速力
You betrayed the Speed Force months ago,
你什么也没说
and you didn't say nothing then.
你从危机中回来也什么都没说
You didn't say nothing when you came back from Crisis either,
你开始注意到
and you started noticing
你的超能力出问题了
something was wrong with your powers.
你可以告诉我的  巴里
You could have told me, Barry.
我们也许可以进入神速力
We might have gone into the Speed Force.
我们或许来得及救它
We might have saved it before it was too late.
我没有
I didn't--I didn't--
反而你不理我
But instead you blew me off...
-我  -一次又一次
- I-- - Again and again!
沃利  我不知道其他人被感染了
I--Wally, I didn't know anyone else was affected.
好吧
All right?
对不起  对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
巴里  你不明白  我们都连在一起
Barry, you don't get it. We are all connected.
当我曾经和神速力对话的时候
When I used to talk with the Speed Force,
有时  它会给我展现不同未来
sometimes it would show me visions of different futures,
不同可能性的幻景
different possibilities of how things could go.
总有一个共同的主线
There was always one common thread.
总有一个极速者
There was always a speedster
能承担我们的职责
that would pick up our mantles,
就像几个世纪以来的一连串闪电
like a chain of lightning stretching through centuries.
我看到我的孩子
I saw my kids...
和他们的孩子一起奔跑
running with their kids.
我看到了诺拉
I saw Nora.
但那一串闪电
But now that chain of lightning...
和我们一起终结
it ends with us.
沃利  还没有太晚  对吧
Okay, Wally, it's not too late though, all right?
我们还有我们的速度
I mean, we still have our speed.
我们能回去  我能救她
We can go back in there. I can save her.
不  你看到了  巴里
No, you saw it, Barry.
神速力已经无法修复
The Speed Force is beyond repair.
如果你以为  在你做了这一切之后
And if you think that I'm gonna bring you back in
我还会把你带回去
after everything that you have done...
沃利
Wally--
你还是去找别的老师吧
You need to find another teacher.
沃利  我们
Wally-- we-- we--
超光粒子增强器准备就绪
The tachyon enhancer's ready.
我无法把意识投射到神速力中
I can't project my consciousness into the Speed Force,
所以我的身体进入神速力时
so I need you to monitor my position
需要你监控我的位置
while I enter it physically.
好的  巴里·艾伦
Certainly, Barry Allen.
启动程序
Okay, start the protocol.
我的宝贝  你回来了
Oh, my beautiful boy, you came back.
当然
Of course I did.
你说神速力正在死亡
You said the Speed Force is dying.
我看到这里到处都是闪电
I see this lightning everywhere.
我能修好它
I can fix it, though.
我可以  告诉我怎么做  我能修好它
I can-- you just-- you tell me what to do and I'll do it.
太晚了
It's too late.
我不接受这个结果  这是我造成的
I won't accept that. I caused this.
我必须要救你
I have to save you.
你没有伤害我
You didn't hurt me.
我攻击了你
I attacked you.
你记得吗
You remember?
巴里  巴里  那不是我死亡的原因
Barry, Barry, that's not why I'm dying.
几个月前  一种物质进入神速力
A few months ago, a substance entered the Speed Force--
我们从未遇见过这种物质
something that we'd never encountered before.
我们试图控制它  但是它污染了我们
We tried to contain it, but it contaminated us.
破坏了我们能量的平衡
It upset the balance of our energies.
绿色和白色的闪电
The green and white lightning.
这是一种比自然法则更强大的可怕力量
It is infernal power beyond the laws of our nature.
不
No.
你说你和多元宇宙是紧密融合的
You said you're in tune with the multiverse.
那其中是否包括神速力
Does that include the Speed Force?
你可以给我我所需的能量
You could give me the energy boost I need.
危机时  我让幽灵把他的能量给我
During Crisis, I made the Spectre give me his energy
从而再次进入神速力
so I could enter the Speed Force again.
这是我的错
I am responsible.
是我做的
I did this.
我摧毁了神速力
I killed the Speed Force.
我不知道  我不知道
I didn't know. I didn't know.
我不会  我永远不会
I wouldn't have-- I never would have--
我很抱歉  我不知道
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
巴里·艾伦  我们原谅你
Barry Allen, we forgive you.
你做了正确的选择  拯救了我们的宇宙
You did the right thing. You saved our universe.
你无法预见会有什么代价
You never could have foreseen what that cost.
我们彻底离开之前
You only have a few steps left
你还有一些奔跑的时间
before we're gone from you entirely,
我知道你会好好利用
but I know you will use them well.
闪电选择了你
The lightning chose you,
这是我们做过的...
and it was the best decision that we--
是我做过最好的决定
I ever made.
你展现出了最伟大的力量
You showed us the greatest force of all.
我爱你  我爱你
I love you. I love you.
我爱你
I love you,
我的
my beautiful,
我的宝贝
beautiful boy.
中城警局
神速力消失了
The Speed Force is dead?
我不知道该说什么好
I don't even know what to say.
你还有超能力吗
Do you still have your powers?
据我所知
From what I can figure out,
我们体内还有一些残留的神速力
we still have a residual amount of Speed Force inside us.
但是随着我们的使用  会越来越少  直到
But the more we use up, the less we have left until--
直到彻底消失
Until it's gone forever?
我的天啊  儿子  我不知道
Oh, my God, son, I didn't--
我无法想象你在经历什么
I can't even imagine what you're going through.
还有巴里
And Barry.
爸爸  这都是他的错
Dad, this is his fault.
他几个月前就应该来找我
He could've come to me months ago.
我们可能会解决这件事
We might've fixed things.
但是他却像以前那样
But instead, he had to do what he always does
而且认为他是唯一可以搞定这件事的人
and assume he's the only one that can handle it.
沃利  你有必要跟他这样说吗
Well, Wally, did you even need to tell him like that?
我们都知道巴里自己就会
I mean, we both know that Barry
恨不得把自己打一顿
will beat himself up all by himself.
没错
He will.
我刚才一点都不禅  对吗
I guess that wasn't very Zen of me at all, was it?
沃利  请你坐下
Wally, sit down please.
你还记得你第一次见我时的样子吗
Do you remember what you were like when we first met?
我记得
'Cause I do.
你任性  倔强
You were petulant, stubborn.
每件小事都会让你生气
Every little thing pissed you off.
你不想要父亲  姐妹  或兄弟
You didn't want a father or a sister or a brother,
但你看看你现在的样子
but look at the man that you are now
你成了一位敏感  聪明
the sensitive, intelligent, compassionate man
有同情心的男人
that you have become,
这不是因为某种神秘的能量在起作用
and it's not because of some mystical energy source out there.
那是因为你的努力
It's because you did the work.
你现在的职责就是继续做那些
Now your responsibility is to continue
让你变成现在这样的事
to do the work to be that man.
你明白我的意思吗  儿子
Do you understand me, son?
队长  我们拘留的另一个线人在等你
Captain, we've got the other informant waiting in custody.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是那个弗里达·诺维科夫的案子
Uh, this is that Frida Novikov case.
她被驱逐出境了  因为我们有两个线人
She got deported because two of our informants
打入了她的走私集团
were part of her smuggling ring,
其中一个是你在直升机事故里认识的朋友
one of them being your friend from the helicopter accident,
玛丽亚·沃尔科娃
Maria Volkova.
难怪诺维科夫会盯上玛丽亚
That's why Novikov targeted Maria.
她是来报仇的
She's out for revenge.
我会把另一位证人纳入联邦证人保护计划
Well, the other informant I'm gonna put in WITSEC soon.
我回头再找你  好吗
I will find you later, okay?
无论你现在所经历的
Hey, whatever you're going through
关于神速力和你能力的问题是什么
with the Speed Force and your powers,
巴里都会有同样的经历
Barry is going through the same thing.
别忘了  我爱你
Remember that. I love you.
我爱你
I love you.
现在不行  凯特
Not right now, Cait.
我正忙着弄移动巴里智脑单元
I'm busy with the mobile BARI unit.
我直说吧
Let me get this straight.
你试图用生物工程的方法来阻止超能力者
You were trying to bioengineer a formula to stop a meta-human,
而不是打电话给你的
and rather than call your friend
生物工程师朋友  你用了蓝牙吗
who's a bioengineer, you went with Bluetooth?
对  我在试图阻止乌龟人二代
Yeah, I'm trying to stop Turtle 2 here.
对  我知道  你一直在忙这件事
Yeah, I know. It's all you've been doing.
根本没时间找我
You don't have any time for me.
纳什向你求助时  你直接拒绝了他
You totally blew off Nash when he asked for your help.
你还是继续你的旅行吧
I mean, you might as well still be on your trip.
对  也许我的旅行
Yeah, well, maybe my trip
并不像计划的那样
didn't turn out exactly as planned.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你去探索了埃及古墓  还有亚特兰蒂斯
You got to raid Egyptian tombs and explore Atlantis.
我以为  经历了这些冒险之后
I thought, after all those adventure,
我回来就大变样了
I would come back different,
像沃利  你或冰霜一样
like Wally or like you and Frost,
但我走遍了这个世界  然后我
but I went around the world, and I...
我觉得自己又回到了原点
And I feel like I'm back where I started.
西斯科  我知道你感觉有愧
Cisco, I know you feel responsible,
但我们会阻止乌龟人二代的  我保证
but we're gonna stop Turtle 2. I promise.
我们是闪电侠小队  这是我们的工作
We're Team Flash. It's what we do.
但与此同时  我想知道你是否
But in the meantime, I wonder if maybe you don't have
还有其他的责任要去承担
some other responsibilities that you'd like to address--
某个跟你比较亲近的
ones that are a little closer to home.
你说得对
You're right.
我处理这项工作的时候
While I'm doing that,
尖端科研实验室
也许我的生物工程师朋友会愿意接手
maybe my friend the bioengineer would like to take over.
当然
Absolutely.
我一直在找你  哥们
I've been looking for you, man.
我以为你会在家里
I thought maybe you'd be home.
不
No.
我还没准备好告诉爱瑞丝
I'm not ready to tell Iris.
我没准备好告诉任何人
I'm not ready to tell anyone.
我发现了神速力到底发生了什么
I found out what really happened to the Speed Force.
它死亡是因为我在危机里做的事
It died because of what I did in Crisis.
我获得了幽灵的能量
I took the Spectre's energy
使我可以进入神速力
so I could enter the Speed Force.
他的能量衍生了崩溃
His energy started a meltdown,
现在它消失了  沃利
and now it's gone, Wally...
永远  因为我做过的事
for good because of what I did.
你是在试图拯救世界
You were trying to save the universe.
无论哪个英雄都会那么做
Any hero would have made that call.
我也会那么做
I would've made that call.
无垢曾经给我讲过一个故事
Amala told me a story once
讲的是一位丢失独子的妈妈
about a mother who lost her only son.
她曾是那么痛心切骨
She was so heartbroken,
她求佛陀把他带回来
she asked the Buddha to bring him back to life.
他说他会的
He said he would...
但是他有一个要求
but he had one request...
要一粒取自没有失去过心爱之人
a mustard seed from a family
的家庭中的芥菜籽
that had never lost a loved one.
所以她挨家挨户的要种子
So she went from neighbor to neighbor asking for seeds,
当她问道
and when she would ask,
"你家里有谁失去过心爱之人吗"
"Has anyone in your family lost someone?"
答案总是有
The answer was always yes.
佛陀在试图让她明白
The Buddha was trying to have her understand
尽管她承受了很多痛苦
that as much as she suffered,
但她不孤单
she wasn't alone.
当我发现神速力要死亡的时候
When I found out the Speed Force was dying...
我也忘记了你有多么痛苦
I forgot how much you were suffering too.
我很抱歉
And I'm sorry.
真心的
I am.
是我做的  你生气我也该受着
I did this. I deserve your anger.
那就对此做些什么
So do something with it.
我们不能因为我们犯过的错而惩罚自己
We can't punish ourselves for the mistakes we've made.
我们无法改变
That's a closed door.
但是我们能为我们的行动负责
But we can take responsibility for our actions...
无论要克服多么大的障碍
no matter how great the obstacle to overcome.
这也是无垢教你的
Amala teach you that too?
不是
No.
是你教的
You did.
各位  我们遇上麻烦了
Guys, we've got a problem.
面部识别刚刚发现弗里达·诺维科夫在中城警局外
Facial rec just picked up Frida Novikov outside CCPD.
你真的认为一个罪犯需要这么多后援吗
You really think one criminal's worth all this backup?
如果这个文件是对的
If this file is right,
我不认为诺维科夫会投降
I don't think Novikov is gonna give up,
我不会把另一个线人纳入联邦证人保护计划
and I'm not putting another informant into WITSEC
除非我们准备充足
unless we're prepared.
慢着  队长  慢慢的
Pomedlenneye, Captain. Slow down.
十年来第一支最低水平的股票
奥尔加·朱拉夫列夫在哪
Where is Olga Zhuravlev?
我知道她在这  带她过来
I know she's here. Bring her to me.
好让你把她变成一堆骨头吗
So you can turn her into a pile of bones?
我只是拿回她从我身上偷走的东西  计时开始
I am just taking from her what she stole from me: time!
现在  给你五分钟把她给我带过来
Now, you have five minutes to bring her to me
不然你们都得死
or you all will die.
她挟持了乔
She has Joe.
西斯科在想办法阻止诺维科夫
Cisco was working on a way to stop Novikov.
那他人呢
So where is he?
请进
Come in.
我想为我混蛋的行为道歉
I wanted to apologize for being a jerk.
但是我想改正
But I wanna make it right,
我们做些多功能鬼魂搜捕怎么样
so what do you say we do some multiversal ghost busting?
危机  不停的给我们找事
Ah, Crisis, the gift that keeps on giving, huh?
你不是纳什
You're not Nash.
你好  西斯科
Hello, Cisco.
-斯旺  -没错
- Thawne. - That's right.
现在  我们说到哪了
Now, where were we?
永别了
Good-bye.
你在纳什的身体里  没有超能力
You're in Nash's body. No powers.
我不需要我的超能力也能杀你
I don't need my powers to kill you.
纳什
Nash?
但是他充满了憎恨
But he's so full of hatred.
那不是纳什
That's not Nash.
新的终极速度-X已经可以用在诺维科夫身上
The new Velocity-X is ready to use on Novikov.
我必须把它放入一个注射枪里
I just have to put it into an injector gun.
不过我们不能在这里用
But we can't run it there.
如果用了  我们会消耗速度的
If we do, we'll use up speed,
而我们没法确定还能剩下多少
and we have no idea how much we have left.
不  我们能
Yes, we can.
我们只要有条理地用就行了
We just have to use it responsibly.
中城警局  尖端科研实验室
好吧  直达中城警局是最快的路线
Okay, the fastest route to CCPD is in a straight line.
中城警局  尖端科研实验室
我们可以跑  但是需要不断穿墙
We can run it. We just have to phase as we go.
准备好了
It's ready.
你跟我一起去吗
You with me?
永远陪着你
Always.
时间到了  队长
Time's up, Captain.
诺维科夫  停下来  你没必要这么做
Novikov, stop. You don't have to do this.
我知道没必要  但我想这么做
I know I don't have to. I want to.
再废话  我就让他老个一千年
Zip off again, and I'll age him 1,000 years.
听我说  听我说
Listen to me. Listen.
我们没法补偿你失去的时光
We can't do anything to make up for the time that you lost,
但是你剩下的时间
but if you take responsibility
是你可以承担责任的
for the time that you have left,
你不会再失去什么了  我保证
you won't lose anymore. I promise.
拜托让我们帮助你
Please let us help you.
我不需要你们的帮助
I don't want your help.
我们知道
We know.
谢谢你的建议  闪电侠
Thanks for the tip, Flash.
让我们看看你怎么操控我们这的时间
Let's see how you handle our version of time.
我抱着她
I held her in my arms.
我又一次看着她死去
I watched her die all over again.
因为我神速力才会消失
The Speed Force is dead because of me,
因为我的选择
because of my choices.
我只是想救下所有人
I just wanted to save everyone.
想救下你
To save you.
你已经做到了
And you did.
巴里  这都不是你的错
Barry, none of this is your fault.
但现在我再也救不了任何人了
Now I won't be able to save anyone.
如果没有超速力我还能做什么
What am I supposed to do without my speed?
也许这样才是最好的
Maybe this is for the best.
什么意思
What?
凡事皆有因果  对吗
Everything happens for a reason, right?
也许你本来就不应该永远都当闪电侠
Maybe you weren't supposed to be the Flash forever.
我是说  难道你就没想过
I mean, don't you think that after everything
神速力让你经历了这么多之后
the Speed Force has put you through--
所有的痛苦  所有的伤心  所有的伤亡...
all the pain, all the heartache, all the death...
你难道不觉得你值得拥有一份真正的生活吗
Don't you think you deserve a real life?
巴里  你所承担的那些全世界的问题
Barry, all the world's problems on your shoulders--
本就不应该是你要去承担的负担
that shouldn't have been your burden to bear.
你是认真的
You're serious.
是的
I am.
这也许是我们拥有正常生活的机会
This could be our chance to have a normal life,
组建一个家
to start a family.
你值得跟大家一样幸福
You deserve to be happy just like everyone else.
你难道不想这样吗
Don't you want that?
巴里  你需要马上来管道监狱
Barry, we need you in the Pipeline right now.
有些东西你必须看看
There's something you need to see.
不知为何  他占据了纳什的身体
Somehow, he's taken over Nash's body.
-闪电侠  -斯旺
- Hi, Flash. - Thawne.
你想干什么
What do you want?
我一直想干什么呢
What do I always want?
我想杀了你
To kill you.
我已经没有耐心了
And I'm done being patient.
我等不及割开你的喉咙了
I can't wait to slit your throat.
到那时  在我出去之后
When I do, when I get out--
相信我
believe me.
我会出去的
I will get out.
我会杀了你...
I'm going to kill you...
然后我会杀了你的家人
and then I'm going to kill your family,
接着我还要杀了你的朋友
and then I'm going to kill your friends.
我要杀了你所有的朋友
I'm gonna kill all your friends,
就从你的新朋友纳什开始
starting with your new pal Nash.
-不行  -不行
- No. - No?
不管你对他做了什么  我们都会阻止你的
Whatever you've done to him, we're gonna stop you.
但难道不是这样
But isn't it true...
短短几周之后
that in a few short weeks,
你将没有能力来阻止我  对吗
you're going to be powerless to stop me, right?
因为你的神速力已经死了
Because your Speed Force is dead.
我能感受到
I can feel it.
这就是你的下场  巴里
And that's what you get, Barry,
信任这么一个弱小又可悲的力量的下场
for trusting such a puny, pathetic force.
这也是为什么我创造自己的力量
That's why I built my own.
我会来的
And I'm coming.
我会来找你的
I'm coming for you.
没什么可说的了
We're done here.
时间不多了
Tick-tock.
硬字幕9【不知道该硬哪里】
他说神速力死了是什么意思
What did he mean, the Speed Force is dead?
你确定这么快就要走吗
You sure you wanna go already?
如果想要赶上下一个维和部队项目
If I'm gonna get to the next Peace Corps project in time,
我就必须得走了
I gotta get going.
如果你坐飞机去
You know, it'd be a whole lot faster
会快很多
if you just got a flight.
我知道  但是我必须步行
I know, but I need to walk.
我需要有开放的心态
I need to have an open mind,
准备好迎接在失去了我的能力的情况下
be ready to embrace new ways
用新的方式帮助他人
of helping others without my powers.
我对此非常遗憾  儿子
I'm so sorry about that, son.
很明显我也不希望
I obviously didn't
你这一趟回家是这样的结局
want your trip home to end like that.
没关系  爸爸
It's okay, Dad.
即便事情没有像你所期待的那样发展
Even if things don't unfold the way you expected,
也不要气馁或者放弃
don't be disheartened or give up.
坚持前行的人会获得最后的胜利
The one who continues to advance will win in the end.
你如今听起来比我更像个家长
You sound more like a parent than I do now.
这都是禅修
Oh, you know, it's a Zen thing.
我爱你  爸爸
I love you, Dad.
我也爱你  非常爱你
I love you too-- too damn much.
-你要保重  好吗  -会的
- You be careful, okay? - Mm-hmm, yes.
爸爸  帮我留意爱瑞丝  好吗
Dad, keep an eye on Iris for me, will you?
她跟以往有些不同
There's something different about her.
请确保她一切都好
Just make sure she's okay.
好的  好的  当然
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah, of course.
-再见  -再见
- Bye-bye. - Bye.
幽灵能量
Spectre energy.
好吧  那只不过是我们还不了解的一种能量
Okay, yeah, well, that's just energy we don't understand yet.
我们能弄明白的  对吧
That's something we can figure out, right?
当然  我们能做一些测试
Absolutely. We can run some tests,
想办法追踪它
figure out how to track it--
谢了  伙计们  不过我希望你们帮我做点别的
Thanks guys, but I want your help with something else.
我一直在想斯旺所说的话
I've been thinking about what Thawne said--
你是说他如何把我们都杀掉吗
You mean how he's gonna kill us all?
我也一直在想
Yeah, me too.
他是如何建造自己的能量来源的
How he built his own power source--
负神速力
the Negative Speed Force.
如果他能建造一个  那么
If he can make one, then...
我们也可以
So can we.
我需要你们帮忙建造一个人造的神速力
I need your help to build an artificial Speed Force.
那样我就能拿回我的神速力
That's how I can get my speed back.
无法删除照片
过滤器仍在加载
我以为我已经删掉了
I thought I deleted this.
检测到异常特征
是否允许棱镜过滤
爱瑞丝
Iris?
我不是爱瑞丝
Yeah, I'm not Iris.
抱歉让你以这种方式得知
Sorry you had to find out this way.
等等  等等  不要
Wait--wait, no--
《中城市民》